Finding Aid for the Stephen P. Heyneman Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Stephen P. Heyneman Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0555
5.88 linear_feet
The Stephen P. Heyneman (1943- ) papers were donated to Vanderbilt University by Heyneman in 2003 and encompass his twenty-two year career with the World Bank. Since 2000 he has been Professor of International Education Policy at Vanderbilt University.
Biography
Stephen P. Heyneman obtained his Bachelor of Arts in Political Science in 1964 from the University of California at Berkley, a Master of Arts in African Area Studies in 1965 from the University of California at Los Angeles, and a Master of Arts and Doctorate of Comparative Education in 1973 and 1975 from the University of Chicago.
He taught school from 1968 to 1969 in Malawi and was Director of a Ugandan Primary School Equality Project from 1971 to 1972. He returned to the United States in 1972 and taught at Chicago Elementary Schools while earning his PhD.
Stephen P. Heyneman started working for the Education Department of the World Bank in 1977 helping research education quality and design policies to support educational effectiveness. Between 1984 and 1989 he was in charge of external training for senior officials world-wide in educational policy and lending strategy, first in the Middle East and North Africa and later for 27 countries of Europe and Central Asia.
In 1998 he was appointed Vice President in charge of international operations of an education consultant firm in Alexandria, Virginia. In September 2000 he was appointed Professor of International Education Policy at Vanderbilt University.
Scope and Content
The Stephen P. Heyneman Papers consist of six linear feet of material from his work with the World Bank from 1978 to 1994. They are comprised of Chronological Files he collected during his twenty-two years at different posts for the World Bank.
The papers are arranged into one series, the Chronological Files. At the end of the papers are business plans and two folders of materials from specific projects on which Mr. Heyneman worked.
The papers were significantly damaged in a water leak and have serious mold issues. The papers have been cropped when able to remove the affected portions and have been treated with alcohol to retard and mold spores left on the papers. These treatments were completed in 2005.
- Series I. Chronological Files
  - October 1978 – June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - October 1978 – June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - October 1978 – June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - October 1978 – June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - October 1978 – June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - October 1978 – June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - July 1979 – February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - February 16, 1980 – December 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - January 1981 – January 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - March 1982 – February 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - March 1982 – February 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - March 1982 – February 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - March 1982 – February 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - March 1982 – February 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - March 1982 – February 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - March 1983 – October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - March 1983 – October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - March 1983 – October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - March 1983 – October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - March 1983 – October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - October 1983 – June 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - October 1983 – June 1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - October 1983 – June 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - February 11, 1985 – May 8, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - February 11, 1985 – May 8, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - February 11, 1985 – May 8, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - February 11, 1985 – May 8, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - February 11, 1985 – May 8, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - May 10, 1985 – August 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - May 10, 1985 – August 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - May 10, 1985 – August 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - May 10, 1985 – August 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - May 10, 1985 –August 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - January 1986 –June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - January 1986 –June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - January 1986 –June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - January 1986 –June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - January 1986 – June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - July 1986 – December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - January 1987 – June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - July 1987 – December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - January 1988 – June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - July 1988 – December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - July 1988 – December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - July 1988 – December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - July 1988 – December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - July 1988 – December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - July 1988 – December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - January 1989 – June 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - January 1989 – June 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - January 1989 – June 1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - January 1989 – June 1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - January 1989 – June 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - January 1989 – June 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - July 1989 – December 1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - January 1990 – July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - August 1990 – March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - April 1991 – August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - September 1991 – January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - February 1992 – July 1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - August 1992 – November 1992 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - December 1992 – April 1993 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - May 1993 – July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - August 1993 – October 1993 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - November 1993 – February 1994 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - March 1994 – July 1994 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Production of Textbooks – Hungary H.N.I.E. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - E.M.P.T.H. Seminar Science Study Package (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Business Plan (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Business Plan (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Business Plan (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Business Plan (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Business Plan (Box 14, Folder 17)